so back in February I received the
following letter from a student at
Linfield College and according to its
website with campuses in McMinnville
Portland and a prestigious online
program Linfield College is a premier
choice in the Pacific Northwest for a
high quality traditional liberal arts
education want to learn more contact us
for details about our degree and
certificate program offerings a student
there who I won't name sent me the
follow letter here dr. Peterson
I'm an undergraduate student in Linfield
College in McMinnville Oregon the
international students for liberty
conference recently granted me a small
sum to organize pro Liberty events on
campus with an emphasis on the
importance of free speech I'm writing to
ask you if you're accepting speaking
invitations at this time and if your
schedule sometime between now and May
would allow it to help narrow down my
options I would like to offer you $1500
and an invitation to speak here this
spring semester your travel and
accommodation costs will also be covered
I perceive Linfield as an institution at
an ideological crossroads I feel it is
my responsibility to pick the most
effective voice possible for helping
Linfield chart a course that will ensure
its future as a place of reason and
academic integrity after listening to
many of your lectures and interviews I
believe your message is ideal for our
campus honest and productive
argumentation is one of your specialties
Linfield would greatly benefit from
being introduced to your ideas on the
subject we are a small College of
roughly 2,000 students situated in quiet
wine country your work continues to have
a deep impact on my personal and
intellectual growth I'd be honored to
hear from you
thank you for your time and
consideration
so after considering it for a while I
agreed to come and speak at Linfield
College on March 18th I received a note
from the invitation student the inviting
student who said good morning dr.
Peterson
I would be overjoyed to confirm a date
so we went about doing that on April 7th
he replied to me again to update me he
said the talk will be held in IC e
auditorium in Melrose Hall April 24th
beginning at 7 p.m. I'm referring to the
event simply as a talk with Jordan
Pederson because his speaking style
allows for a lot of fluidity and topic
however the core theme to the event is
the importance of freedom of speech
especially in higher education some of
the administration / student government
have begun to threat about the potential
for people to feel open quote offended
and oppressed close quote by Peterson's
talk it's more pushback than I expected
at Lynn field but I don't think it's a
cause for concern I'm fighting hard to
keep their worries at bay and there's a
very supportive group of students and
community members who have my back
free speech will win on April 17 the
following article appeared in student
newspaper by Thalia Neel editor-in-chief
it's called hate symbol on ball riled
campus the Linfield young americans for
liberty groups free speech ball outside
of Walker Hall on April 12th received
attention from students in faculty when
the student drew Pepe the Frog which has
recently been appropriated by white
supremacist groups Linfield College
posted a picture of the ball on its
Instagram account
but it was later removed because of the
frogs association with alt right groups
as soon as it was pointed out that the
photo included the image the Instagram
post was removed president Thomas Kelly
said the free speech ball event the
first event in the speak freely a series
of Linfield encouraged students to
express themselves by writing and
drawing on the ball to promote free
speech Pepe the Frog is a popular
internet meme that has often appeared in
humorous ways the anti-defamation league
has lifted Pepe the Frog on its hate
symbols database I only heard about it
secondhand and I understand that it is a
place for free speech but in all reality
it was certainly done in very poor taste
Junior
John Christian
said according to its website the yal
mission is to open quote identify
educate train and mobilize youth
activists committed to winning on
principles our goal is to cast the
leaders of tomorrow and reclaim the
policies candidates and direction of our
government close quote
a member of yal drew the Pepe the Frog
on the ball but asked to remain
unidentified
open quote I knew the person who drew
Pepe he didn't draw to be negative he
drew it to be funny close quote
senior Parker Wells a member of Y al
said he continued we understand some
groups appropriated the image but any
image can be appropriated Wells said his
goals with the free speech ball
were to give people thinking about the
rights to free expression and to bring
more attention to the yal group he said
I understand that it's necessary to set
limits but I don't think this cartoon
frog is a limit to set for free speech I
find it unfortunate that people can't
enjoy this event because of the frog
image as a part of its speak freely
series why Al is bringing dr. Jordan
Peterson to campus on Monday April 24th
the group is also showing the
documentary the red pill on Tuesday May
2nd professor of English res me dot Val
Erstad said open quote I find both the
invitation of Jordan Pederson and the
screening of the documentary the red
pill by the young Americans for Liberty
Club extremely problematic problematic
because neither Pedersen nor the film
will be promoting dialogues about
gendered inclusions but rather be
promoting a dangerous and offensive
logic of gendered exclusions dodgeballer
staff continued the promotion of such
exclusionary practices greatly
threatened safe spaces for our students
staff and faculty who belong to
marginalized groups and violates our
ethos of upholding mutual respect on our
campus
the president's Diversity Committee will
hold a discussion at 5:30 p.m. on Monday
in the Pioneer reading room titled free
speech what it is and what it is not the
discussion will examine free speech and
members of the Lindsay
community are encouraged to attend so
that's the end of that newspaper article
so I read that it was forwarded to me
soon after I tweeted the following
methods open quote I'm violating some
more safe spaces soon Linfield College
April 24th well on April 19th I received
a letter from the student who'd
organized my talk he said things have
gone nuclear
this email the one I'm going to read to
you was just sent to all of Linfield one
of the stipulations they are referring
to is the contract which they rejected
because it was a day late our club is
currently looking for space in downtown
in McMinnville to hold Peterson stark
instead the media is likely getting
involved I'm sorry for this insanity we
tried very hard to keep things civil
here so here is the letter sent out to
the entire community Linfield community
I am writing on behalf of the Linfield
cabinet as officer in charge while
president Kelley is out I want to let
the Linfield community know that the ASL
see Associated Students of Linfield
College have determined it will not fund
dr. Jordan Peterson's appearance next
week because stipulations for the event
were not met by the requester young
Americans for liberty since the
authorization parameters were not
satisfied the college will not hold
Steve and on April 24 among the
stipulations was that the event was to
be a private Linfield College only event
by his own tweet yesterday to a hundred
and seven thousand followers dr.
Peterson indicates he would be open
quote violating more safe spaces soon
Linfield College close quote like-minded
supporters from outside our community
have responded affirmatively our policy
on anti harassment protection and
academic freedom states that open quotes
anti-harassment policies are not
intended to limit the free exchange of
opinions or the vigorous debate over
ideas however intimidation harassment
rotation and the use or threat of force
are incompatible with the preservation
of this freedom the letter continues
based on the speaker's own words this
event no longer presents the possibility
of academic inquiry within the lineal
community our policy is clear open quote
harassment and intimidation preclude the
very possibility for maintaining an
atmosphere of academic freedom
we cannot welcome speakers when the
stipulations for their appearances are
not met and who attend who intend to
violate the safety of our communities
respectfully Suzan Agri Chippenham
so I wrote a letter to Suzan Agri
Chippenham now you understand that by
this time the flights had been arranged
the accommodation and being arranged
everything was in place and of course
they have known about this for a long
time dear Susan I received a copy of
your letter to the Linfield community
this morning as well as an indication
that my long scheduled talk at Linfield
has been cancelled that is fine I
suppose
except that the plane tickets have been
booked and the hotel reservations have
been made as well as three days taken
out of my schedule at my expense I think
you are treating me and the student
group who invited me in a manner that is
absolutely reprehensible as well as
cowardly and underhanded I have made
arrangements to come to Linfield which
is extremely distant from me and out of
the way in good faith now you cancel it
with a plethora of specious reasons
including your anti harassment policy
although I have harassed no one nor
intimidated exploited or threatened
force had I not previously received
notice of the controversy around my
arrival which is in my opinion
unwarranted I would not have tweeted my
intent to open quote violate safe spaces
close quote
which is a satirical comment in case it
needs to be said obviously you were
looking for any excuse no matter how
trivial to cancel this event you also
note that open quote this event no
longer presents the possibility of
academic inquiry the
in the Linfield community close quote I
might point out that Linfield is a
college not a community and that ideas
need to be discussed in a college you
also state that open quote
anti-harassment policies are not
intended to limit the free exchange of
opinions or the vigorous debate over
ideas close quote and then proceed to do
exactly that you also mentioned that you
have received support from open quote
like-minded supporters close quote from
outside your community which is hardly
surprising or informative given that
they were like-minded you also suggest
that because the contract was delayed
one day that constitutes sufficient
grounds for cancellation even though you
knew perfectly well that the event was
booked and finalized and that such
delays are by no means unheard of in
such situations you might also note that
a guest invited to your college might
expect to be treated with a modicum of
consideration and respect here's what I
plan to do I'm going to make a video
tomorrow morning at the latest reading
this letter on youtube explaining that
my invitation has been revoked what that
means for me and the nature of the
reasons given I will also read this
letter of response from me it should be
watched by about 150,000 viewers many of
whom I imagine will be Linfield alumni
supporters and students I am perfectly
willing to see what they all have to say
then we can let the dust settle where it
may sincerely dr. Jordan V Peterson
professor of psychology University of
Toronto I received absolutely nothing in
response god no they didn't even have
the decency to send me a notification
explaining their rationale nothing so I
was treated as far as I'm concerned with
with well let's call it unprofessionally
and leave it at that so what's the story
now the organizing students tried to
book an alternative venue they didn't
have enough money to rent a suitable
theatre or lecture hall I told them that
they could use my honorarium to pay for
the space which they did the Yamhill
valley new's register.com posted this
update
April 20th off-campus venue found for
controversial speaker Linfield colleges
student government organization this
week withdrew permission for a newly
organized club young Americans for
Liberty to bring a controversial speaker
to campus for a free public talk Monday
the group has responded by lining up an
off-campus location for the presentation
featuring Jordan Peterson a Canadian
professor whose campaign against gender
neutral pronouns is considered offensive
by some to the transgender population
Peterson has been rebooked for 7:00 to
9:00 p.m. at the Falls Event Center
housed in the former Chapel on the
evergreen aviation and Space Museum
campus so on with the show
and you can figure out what I think of
the Linfield administrators who pulled
this stunt on your own thanks for
watching